

albinpaul002@gmail.com • +91 7012789674

SUMMARY

Data engineer with 4.9 years of experience in ETL process and fulfillment of data warehouse project tasks such as data extraction, cleansing, transforming, and loading into the target warehouse database. Proficient in writing SQL queries and have good experience working with DataStage, Unix commands and Shell scripting. Adaptable, excellent team player having good communication and interpersonal skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Wipro Technologies. Project: Banking

Apr 2024 - Present

- Worked on additional features for existing projects and documentation of the enhancements.
- Participated in code reviews, sprint planning and daily scrum meetings.
- · Conduct technical interviews for selecting new resources.

Software Engineer, Virtusa Consulting Services. Project: Optum

Nov 2022 - Apr 2024

- Developed data integration jobs in IBM DataStage based on client requirements and project framework.
- Performance improvement of jobs, unit testing and integration testing.
- Scheduling SQLs, scripts, DataStage jobs in Airflow.

Data Engineer, 5x Pvt Ltd. Project: Mina

Jul 2022 - Oct 2022

- · Worked on building data stack for clients.
- Setting up ETL pipeline, data transformation layer and data reporting layer using various softwares like Fivetran, dbt, Snowflake, Metabase etc.
- Creating reports and dashboards as per client requirement.

System Engineer, Tata Consultancy Services. Project: Sony

Jul 2019 - Jun 2022

- Designed integration jobs in IBM DataStage to combine data from multiple, varied data sources such as RDBMS, SQL and Files.
- Collaborated with business intelligence staff at customer facilities to produce customized ETL solutions for specific goals.
- Developed and delivered reports for business via SAP business objects.
- Team lead for support team.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering

APJ Abdul Kalam Technological University

Jul 2015 - Aug 2019

CGPA 7.51

High School Education

Central Board of Secondary Education

Mar 2014 - Mar 2015

CGPA 9.2

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Technical Skills: IBM DataStage, Unix, SQL, Shell Scripting, Teradata, Python, Airflow, SAP Business Objects, Github, Fivetran, Metabase, DBT
- Languages: English, Hindi, Malayalam
- Certificates: Programming, Data structures and Algorithms using Python
- Awards:
 - 'Walk The Talk' award winner at Tata Consultancy Services.
 - Star Team award winner at Tata Consultancy Services.
- · Hobbies: Badminton, Music, Fishing

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that all the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Albin Paul